Welcome to Using the group block. The<br />group block allows you to group and
style multiple blocks together,<br />simplifying content management and
design.
Learning Outcomes. How to set up a group<br />block and add blocks. How to rename and
organize the list view. How to customize<br />the group block using settings and
styles option. Find documentation about<br />the group block.
Here is an example page that I want to<br />go through first of some options of how
to use the group block. So the first<br />one, I use the group block with a
background image and a heading. I've<br />also added a border and radius. The
second one, I used a group block with an<br />image, heading and paragraph. Also added
a border around that. The third one,<br />example is a group block with a heading
and a gallery block to create the page.
I've opened up a page, and I'm turned on<br />my list view, which is the three slashes
over in the upper left hand corner. I<br />like to have my toolbar at the top. So
if you'd like to do this, you can click<br />on the three dots in the upper right
hand corner and go to top toolbar and<br />turn that on. We're going to add a group
block. So I'll type in group with the<br />slash. I'm just going to click on the
front the first one option, and then I'm<br />going to go over to my styling tools.
I'm going to add my background image,<br />open up my media library, make sure that
you've optimized your images before<br />uploading them, and then add alt text
for accessibility. Now we're going to go<br />and style our image so we have the group
block clicked. I'm going to go up into<br />my tools at the top and go to align, and
I'm going to do a full width on the<br />align. Okay, so now I'm going to go back
over to the right and go to the styles.<br />I'm going to scroll down to minimum
height, and I want to add probably about<br />644 let's try that maybe 645 because I
want to be able to get the hands in<br />there. So we'll start there and make
sure I click Update. And then another<br />tool that you can use is going back up
to the background, where you had the<br />background image, and go to size and
open that up. So this gives you the<br />option to take the main focus and adjust
that so I can adjust that so that the<br />hands are showing, and click update on
that. I'm going to then click on the<br />plus sign within the group block and add
a heading. We make this baking. I'm<br />going to click on the tools and go to
align text center. So we can't see the<br />the heading text very well. So I'm going
to do some styling on that. So I'm going<br />to go over to the styling tools and
click on background, and it opens up my<br />my colors, and I'm just going to pick
the green from here, and then I need to<br />add some padding. So I'm going to go
down to dimensions within the heading<br />block and turn on padding. I'm going to
do two clicks front and top and bottom,<br />and two clicks side to side. I'm also
going to go back up to the group block<br />do a little bit more styling there,
because I want a little bit of space<br />between the heading and the top. So I'm
going to go to styles, I'm going to add<br />some padding for the top and bottom so
that looks good. And then I'm going to<br />add my border. So I'm going to go down
to the border, I'm going to add that<br />same green, and then I'm going to add a
little bit of thickness to it. And then<br />I'm also going to use the radius to show
you how to use that. So we're just going<br />to click on radius, and I'm going to a
radius adds a curve to the corner. So<br />I'm just going to make it very dramatic
and go all the way to 100 and we're<br />going to click update, and we'll refresh
the page, and there's our first block.
For our second example, I'm going to<br />click on the three dots and do an add
after. This time, I'm not going to start<br />with a group block, because I want to
show you how to group blocks together.<br />So let's start with an image. And we're
going to make this one a cookie one, and<br />then I'll add a heading. And I'm going
to grab some text from my example, and I<br />use cupcake ipsum. It's a free site that
you can get filler text from, and this<br />one is just baking, so it's fun.
Alright, so we have our three blocks<br />over here in our list view, and we can
click on the first one and then hit<br />Shift and click on the last one. And
once we have those highlighted, we're<br />going to click on the three dots and we
can scroll down to the group. Okay, so<br />that was simple. Click Update, and then
we can go back on those three dots and<br />click rename, and keep our list view
organized. Okay, so let's go ahead and<br />stop do some styling of this one. This
one, I'm going to do a line to a wide<br />width. Okay, give it a little bit
different in the layout. I'm going to<br />turn off this just because I want the
text to be able to spread out a little<br />bit more. And we'll see when we get all
our styling done on that. I do want to<br />click on the image, because the image is
going to be a little bit big. It doesn't<br />auto with the original. So I'm going to
put in 568, because I want it a little<br />bit smaller. And then I want to align
this to this center. Okay, so we'll<br />click on that, click on the Update
button. And then I also want to add, go<br />back up to our group block, and I want
to add a border around this so I'm going<br />to click on the colors and open that up
and just do a small border there. Click<br />on Update. I'm going to go up and add
some padding. So on this one, I want to<br />add about four clicks of padding, and
then two on the side. Let's do that. And<br />then also, there's an option for this
block spacing. So I want to add a little<br />bit of space in between each of the
three blocks that I'm using. So we'll do<br />that. And I think I have everything.
Let's look at it on the front end. Click<br />and refresh. I forgot to align the text.
So let's go back to the header and we'll<br />align that to the center. There we go.
And we're good for that.
To add our last group block. I'm going<br />to click on the three dots from the
previous group and do an add after I'll<br />type in for a group block. I'll pick the
first option. I'm going to add a<br />heading, and I'll style my heading to
align text center from the toolbar at<br />the top, and then I would add my gallery
here like that, but there is the example<br />has Several different images. So to save
time, I'm going to do a quick back, back<br />up. And what I'm going to do is just do
a copy and paste instead of adding all<br />of the so I'm going to click on that
gallery, go to the three dots, and do a<br />copy so I can add my images quickly. If
I open up the gallery block, you see<br />that they're all individual images.
Okay, so we're going to go back up to<br />our group block. We would rename it. You
guys know how to do that. Now, on this<br />one, I'm going to make it a full width,
okay? And the other thing is to on my<br />layout for the group block. For this
one, I'm going to turn off this toggle,<br />and this is going to make the images
spread out a little bit more. So make<br />sure I click that update, because that's
a big update. I'm going to add a<br />background, so I'm going to click on the
styling, go to background and click on<br />the brown. I need a little bit of
padding here, so I'm going to go down to<br />padding under dimensions and do two
clicks on the top and bottom and two<br />clicks on the side. We'll click update
on that. Think everything looks good.<br />Fingers crossed everyone. We'll do a
refresh, and there we are.
See the resource section for the link to<br />documentation about the group block.
Have fun exploring all the ways to use<br />the group block. Thank you for watching.